## PERSONAL STATEMENT

Simplicity, creativity, and passion have always stood out to me as signs of greatness, and I strive to infuse these traits into everything that I create. I bring unique life experience, communication skills, and a deep love for problem solving to every project. I want to work for awesome companies and create incredible things, so if that is something you are interested in, I would love the opportunity to work with you.

## **SKILLS**

01 Computer		02 Knowledge	
Ruby	Javascript	Team Dynamics	REST Conventions
Rails	Bootstrap	Rapid Learning Skills	Interface Design
AngularJS	Ember.js	00 Design Patterns	Test Driven Development
HTML & CSS	SQL	Agile Web Development	Pair Programming

## **EXPERIENCE**

UI Developer | PNC Bank, Pittsburgh PA | October 2015 to present

- > Fulfill contract developing user facing online banking solutions utilizing JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, HTML, and CSS
- > Work and develop in an extrememly agile environment, participating in code reviews and planning sessions

Rails Contractor | Antir Interactive, Pittsburgh PA | June 2015 to present

- > Work with client team to implement new features for their product, as well as maintain existing codebase and debug issues within a rails application
- > Collaborate with team lead to create more user friendly and mobile responsive site

Rails Developer | OpenArc, Pittsburgh PA | June 2015 to September 2015

- > Fulfilled contract developing consumer based features and applications using Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Ember.js, HTML, CSS and pair based programming.
- > Collaborated with Product Management and User Experience experts regarding product definition, schedule, scope and project-related decisions

Web Developer | Turing Group, Evanston IL | January 2015 to June 2015

- > Worked along with a team following Agile methodologies to develop a single page web application built on AngularJS, Rails, Bootstrap and SQL Server. (rbcs.com)
- > Collaborated on smaller projects utilizing new technologies and creative problem solving

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Music 2004 to 2009 University of Mississippi Master of Music 2009 to 2011 University of Illinois Web Developer Training August to December 2014 Dev Bootcamp, Chicago